Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org
Subtitle by TescoJim.
Nobody move! First one
who moves. I'll drop him!
-You know who I run accounts for?
-Tonight you run them for me! Move!
You know what I was thinking?
That maybe you've
gotten a bit too ambitious.
and that it was your idea.
I'm sure Angelo had nothing to do with it.
and that he'll bring us the
rat who stole all our money.
If you kill me. you won't fix anything.
The real problem is the one who kisses you
and then stabs you in the back.
France'!
[UNREADABLE]
[UNREADABLE 39]
Holy shit—your best friend.
Don't do it.
There's only one Naples.
It's either all of us.
or it's nothing.
They're on us! They're on us!
Go. Angiolè! Go. go!
POLICE!
Run. Angiolè. run! They're catching us!
We're gonna crash too like this!
We made it. kid!
Come here. come on!
We stuck it right up
the Finance Police's ass!
Come on. Don Corrado.
-Long live Corrado Arena!
-Good evening. guys.
Corrado Arena is Naples' father!
Don Corrado. you're number one!
You're the best. Angiolè!
-Don Corra'. you're number one!
-You're too kind.
-Too kind.
-Come on. guys. quick!
Let's get to work—move. boys!
Thanks. thanks. But let's
not waste time. alright?
Come on—move!
Enough with the ceremony...
go unload.
Angiolè. now I get why
they call you 'A Sirena...
'cause out at sea you're a beast.
You know your worth.
and you know the people
you work for don't appreciate it.
I get it—that's why you risk
your life out there at sea.
to be free.
Freedom?
What freedom. Don Corrado?
With all due respect.
but the freedom you're talking
about is only for people like you.
You know what they
call us in Secondigliano?
Little monkeys.
And what chance does a little
monkey have of being free?
I'll give you that chance.
Next week is my daughter's christening.
All the families that matter will be there.
You come too—sit at the table with us.
where the seat you deserve is.
It's an honor. Don Corrado.
If you come. you'll be doing me the honor.
Take care. kid.
-Good evening. everyone.
-Good evening. Don Corrado.
May the Madonna guide him.
May he be with the angels.
Do they know how he died?
Pie'—you don't know anything?
Why are you asking me?
Nobody in the neighborhood talks.
Nobody knows anything.
Enza. have some coffee...
you need to keep your
strength up. for the baby too.
Come on.
He didn't even get to hear him say “Dad.”
What happened?
Whoever did it. I'll never
forgive them till the day I die.
How did your lesson go?
The teacher said I'm improving a lot.
-Really?
-Yes.
-Are you happy?
-So much!
Hi.
Daddy's beautiful girl.
So?
It went really well.
He said I'm improving a lot.
Good girl.
We learned some new songs too.
JEWELRY STORE
Angiolè—already back?
Uncle. good night.
Uncle… Mom was right.
I disappointed her.
I'm not what she hoped for.
You know what your mother did
when she shot the man
who killed your father?
She came back home to feed you.
Even though she knew it wouldn't end well.
she was happy.
because she had you in
her arms—she was smiling.
She told me: “I'm entrusting him to you.
Tell him he's my heart.
and he has to make me proud
I brought him into the world.
Because only then can
my son earn respect...
the respect we never had.”
Angiolè. each of us has our own fate.
I look at you
and I see the man you can become.
Now take this torment
off your shoulders. my son.
Uncle. it's not torment.
It's anger that's eating me alive.
Blondies.
Catcher
[UNREADABLE NA.7]
Alright.
We're done.
Twenty are ours and fifty
go to the Villas. like always.
We do the work and they
give us a miserable cut.
I'm not letting the Villas
step on my face anymore!
Secondigliano is our home.
and I want it to become an empire.
not stay some backwater.
And if you wanna know—
Corrado Arena is already on our side.
he believes in us.
He even invited us to his daughter's
christening. You know what that means?
All the bosses of Naples will be there.
And then there's us.
And does Don Antonio know about this?
We don't work for Corrado Arena...
we work for the Villas.
and we need permission.
After what happened. we can't
do stupid shit like this anymore.
What we can't do is
miss a chance like this.
Guys...
we accept the invitation.
I get what you're saying...
but right now I need
to live quiet. Angiolè.
Mimì—you scared?
You're right.
When I deliver the crates to the Villas.
I'll ask permission.
so we keep him happy—and
make him a sucker too.
Good. Angiolè.
You bring the word of Our Lord
to this sick earth.
but honestly. I can't do it
for less than five million.
This is 500 years old. Don Bene'—
If you ever wanted to sell it.
I never would. You know
for me it's not about money.
I know—for you it's a passion for life
and the story of Our Lord.
but in this filthy world
everything has a price.
And you know what a foreign
collector would pay for it?
A hundred times what I
asked you for. Don Bene'.
Alright. alright.
Come with me.
Just make sure this stays between us.
Thanks a lot. Don Bene'. Have a good day!
You're welcome. you're welcome.
And pray! Always. Don Bene'—always!
Rosà!
Rosalba!
Rosalba. are you deaf?
Sorry. Don Bene'—the tap
was running. I didn't hear you.
You don't need to come
tomorrow. I'm leaving for a few days.
And where are you off to. then?
The Pope wants me in Rome.
-Oh my God. what a wonderful thing!
-Wonderful. yes...
Work. Go on. go on.
Yes.
Bathroom—I need the bathroom...
Fucariè. why are you running like that?
You shitting yourself?
You guessed it—I'm shitting myself.
You got newspaper to wipe your ass?
Yeah—here!
Open up. open up—I'm shitting myself!
Jesus. it stinks in here!
It's like a bomb went off!
So what do we do?
Let's go to Angelo's bar—maybe
he's got a little job for us.
-Yeah. guys. let's go.
-Yeah. let's go.
-Pie'. you coming?
-No.
Pie'. what's up with
you? You're weird today.
Nothing. Manue'.
Pie'. whatever it is. we're with you.
I know.
Pie'. we're one and the same.
If something's eating
at you. you can tell us.
There's a girl I like.
You could've just said that!
-Talk—who is she?
-You don't know her.
Come on! Jesus. Pie'—tell us!
Even if she's from Secondigliano.
you don't know her.
She goes to school. she studies.
her family has money.
Are you serious?
Pie'. you know better than
us how those people see us.
We're trash to them.
Not all of them are like that.
So what— I can't even dream about her?
But you still dream
about playing for Napoli!
What's that got to do with it?
I've got the talent.
Bullshit!
Pie'. if you dream too much
your head gets scrambled.
and then you don't know what's a dream
and what's real.
You're wrong. Manue'.
I know the difference.
Reality is better than dreams.
because dreams—you
just keep them as they are.
but reality? You can change that.
Lello!
-Lellù!
-Look who it is!
Rosalba. get in!
-Get in. Rosalba!
-We'll get out.
Guys. don't bust my balls!
“Don't bust my balls” my ass—move!
Stop busting my balls
and act like grown-ups.
Go!
Hi. Lello. Hi. Cinese.
I was just thinking about you. Le'.
Me?
I've got something for you.
And what is it? Talk.
I'll tell you only if you
take me out tonight...
something really important.
Lello. take her out for a babà.
this big!
Can I have a minute? Just one.
Guys. I don't have a lira.
Rosalba said it's important.
so it's worth making a little sacrifice.
Guys. give me whatever
you've got in your pockets.
-Oh yeah? I've got ass-wiping paper.
-Give it here—it'll do.
Pie'. throw something in too.
Alright.
Put it in your pocket—enough for a snack.
One? And what about me. guys?
You can watch her while she eats.
Move it. Lellù!
So tonight I can come pick you up?
How nice.
Blondies.
Fifty. like always.
-All good.
-Good.
Goodbye.
Angiolè...
I know how much it cost
you to do what you did.
I never doubted you.
I knew you were loyal.
But Dad. Angelo...
Dad doesn't trust anyone.
not even me.
But after what you did.
I think he can't say a word anymore.
About that. there's something
I should ask Don Antonio.
Dad isn't here. He's away
on business—back tomorrow.
But you can tell me. you know.
I'm sorry.
but for certain things I
have to speak to your father.
Dad isn't immortal.
The day will come when you'll answer to me.
When that day comes. I
know exactly which side I'm on.
I've always known.
Excuse me.
Take care.
This.
For me it's only me. swear it?
Yes. I swear.
But now you're telling me?
Will you kiss me?
But now you'll tell me?
[UNREADABLE NA 932246]
Hi. Pietro.
Hi. Imma.
I'm glad to see you're doing well.
Thanks.
Anyway. you don't follow a
young lady in secret. you know.
I wasn't following you in secret...
I was following you. Period.
Anyway. you play well.
and you've got a beautiful voice too.
Thank you.
But I'm not that good.
I have to do more if I want
to make my dream come true.
And what would that be?
I mean… what is it?
Once I graduate. I want to get into
the best university in
the world for musicians.
Nice.
And where is it?
In New York.
That far?
I know—it's on the other
side of the world. but...
it's my dream. and dreams are
meant to be chased. don't you think?
That's normal.
-What is it? Did I say something wrong?
-No—when have you ever?
Actually. it's a beautiful thing.
And you?
Do you have something like that?
Something you'd do anything for?
-Come on. I have to go to work.
-Yeah. I have to go too.
I've got class at the Conservatory.
We can walk part of the way together.
No. I'm going the other way.
Bye.
Guys. we gotta go—move!
And we're not waiting for Pietro?
Guys. we've waited for him long enough.
Maybe you didn't get it—
Pietro's lost his head over that girl.
His sweetheart—the good family's daughter.
Let's go. Enough.
Who is it?
I knew you'd come!
Shut up. idiot!
If I left you alone. you know
what a mess you'd make!
Pie'. you're number one!
This house is beautiful!
Pie'. the cabinet's here.
-You sure the priest isn't here?
-Don't worry!
Cinese told me he's in Rome with the Pope.
Move.
Harder.
Nice!
Jesus...
It's beautiful!
-It's scary.
-Jesus!
Let's go.
What's that?
Guys. someone's here.
Guys. someone's really here!
-We're fucked!
-Shut up!
-Wait. let me put this down.
-Get over here.
Damn me for taking it!
Don't make noise!
Easy. easy. guys...
They're coming here.
Pie'. what the fuck do we do now?
Yeah—let's go to bed. my girl!
Manue'...
they're taking too long.
What could've happened. To'?
How the hell should I know?
-So what do we do now?
-What do you want to do?
Pray.
Pray to Our Lady of Mount Carmel.
Good! Like that!
The bathroom?
End of the hall.
Freeze!
Hands up.
Robbing God's house!
You've got no conscience!
Now I'm calling the police. and you'll
end up in Poggioreale for 15 years.
You're calling the police?
With all due respect—what will
you tell them when they ask you
who the lady was in bed with you?
What lady? There's nobody here!
And who do you think people will believe?
Me—or three thieves like you?
That's a good question.
I'd like to know too. right. Lellù?
I can't wait to tell everyone.
Fucariè—how did the priest do it?
Ooh! Aaah!
Yes!
You're as beautiful as the Madonna!
What's going on?
Nothing—come on. everything's fine.
These boys are leaving.
Yes ma'am—goodbye.
-Goodbye. uncle.
-Take care.
Take care. uncle.
Talk.
While I was loading the cigarettes.
Don Corrado invited me.
And what did he invite you to?
His daughter's christening.
I thought it was better to
speak to you right away.
since we're yours.
I wouldn't want Don Corrado
to take it out on you if I said no.
You did right. Angiolè—you did right.
But listen to me.
These things aren't for you.
These are important occasions.
People like you could end up embarrassed.
Don't worry. I'll talk to Corrado.
and I'll tell him that on
the day of the christening
you had to do important things for me
that couldn't be put off.
But don't worry...
we'll bring you and your friends
your party favor ourselves.
As you say. Don Anto'.
Sorry to bother you.
Go.
May the Madonna guide you.
Lawyer. eat.
Kid—Dad. eat before it gets cold.
Jesus—if we sell this thing.
we'll make a shitload of money. Pie'!
You sell it and then what?
Buy clothes?
If everything goes well
you buy a scooter. and then?
-You run out of money. the party's over.
-So what do you want to do?
Me? I'd treat myself to a
proper lunch like a gentleman
in an amazing restaurant!
We'll make a hundred
thousand. Fucariè. I promise.
-Pie'. where the fuck are you going?
-Trust me.
-Where are you going?
-Pietro!
Where's he going now?
-Who the fuck understands him?
-Seriously!
Let's go. guys.
Kid. who are you looking for?
Sorry to bother you—I'd
like to speak to Don Angelo.
Wait here. I'll see if he can come.
What are you doing here?
I didn't think I'd see you again.
Why?
Because the other day at the
funeral you looked at me weird.
and you stopped coming to the bar.
I got the feeling that...
like you were avoiding me.
I got scared.
Go back home.
And forget what you saw.
Where am I supposed to go? Huh?
I've got nobody. I've got nothing!
No mom. no dad.
There's only one thing I know:
my dream is to be like you.
not a slave under a boss.
It's for you.
It's sacred.
like the respect I have for you.
Tomorrow I'll come pick you up.
And bring all your boys.
I'll dress you like gentlemen.
We're going to a christening.
COMMUNAL SHOWERS
We only get one life.
and if we throw it away. what's left?
Bitterness. disappointment. injustice.
And how
can we even come to feel satisfaction
in the very moment of our last breath.
because the life we were
given—we truly lived it?
You see. we are all brothers...
we in here. together
with our people out there.
Free brothers
who fight united for the good of the poor.
Move out of the way.
I killed.
Is there a procession here this morning?
Let me through.
Move out of the way.
-He's on the exploiter's side.
-Shut that shithole down!
What the fuck are you looking at?
That's why he's against us!
And for that he will
answer to God's justice.
of which I am the
humble hand on this earth.
I don't have time for
this bullshit this morning.
Fairy tales are for children.
and this isn't church.
I'm sorry you're so blind
you can't see Christ
in each of these faces.
and so deaf you mistake
the Lord's word for noise.
You done?
Now get the fuck out—I need to wash!
God's will has been done!
And it shows us how to defend
ourselves from our enemies!
NEXT EPISODE
What if I don't want
to wait until that day?
That means unloading French
heroin in Naples for the first time.
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org